[Music]
thank you
hello and welcome to hollow talk the
internet radio broadcast for lasers and
holography enjoyed by listeners
throughout the world I'm Frank de
Freitas and I'll be your host for each
installment bringing you news guests and
everything holographic now please enjoy
the latest show
[Music]
hello hello is this Dr Mitchell yes this
is Frank de Freitas with the holotalk
show oh yes yes yes yes how are you I'm
fine thank you uh first off uh perhaps
you could tell the listeners a little
bit about your background specifically
with this Quantum hologram in your
research with ESP I mean we're all aware
of your uh your Apollo history and and
um
maybe you could let the listeners know a
little bit about how you got involved
with this quantum holography theory and
also about your experiments with ESP
from most of the things that we've read
uh it says that a lot of these
discoveries and and thoughts of years
occurred on your trip back from the moon
but actually this was a lifelong
interest of yours wasn't it much more as
a result of
yes
how long have you been involved with the
theories behind Quantum holography of
the quantum hologram and your research
in ESP 12 years
and you've you started this in in what
way what led you to
led to it was
uh
I was living a lecture at Cambridge
University
yeah
five I believe okay
um
on a a model of thinking that I was
using
concerned with my
okay
for that lecture
for trying to understand the nature of
conscious
conscious cause conscious conscious
means
that are Nation is how we know anything
so I was gave a lecture on this and
after that lecture I
a person in the audience came up to me
and said I think we've recently
discovered
to meet on the bones of what you're what
you're talking about and actually
validation
so I said well let's go hear about it
and that would Dr
IP is now retired from CERN
in Switzerland
and he told me about
the Walter shims work in the quantum
hologram and
applying it mostly
MRI
life and how to improve the MRI
and he
he had been called the quantum hologram
study of consciousness
how we're aware at all
block
what did he say about the quantum
hologram well first of all the quantum
hologram is a non-mocal informational
structure
and person and
it demonstrates because
it's rooted in the emission absorption
phenomenon
and reabsorb energy even down to
the level of zero degrees Kelvin uh
and is not local
then
it clearly is a Quantum phenomenon and
he had analyzed it with using the
conventional direct Heisenberg nil
potentially
and that was
approach to it
and it could now validated several
several times over in my work
that this is really at the basis of how
we perceive information
at all that at the very bottom of our
perceptual
tuned to the
[Applause]
internet
and we have established that over and
over again and
experiments in the laboratory
you cannot Shield
this type of information
that you can put Barenaked cages and all
sorts of shielding around it and
communicate through that barrier
and that has been well demonstrated in
hundreds of experiments if not thousands
but this time
therefore like gravitation we're dealing
essentially what you're saying is it's
possible to transverse the space between
point A and B without actually traveling
the distance well certainly
if that would suggest that because
Einstein called spooky action in
additions and that would suggest
since matter is energy also and
information there's patterns
that
maybe at some point beam me up Scotty is
a real possibility absolutely and
certainly
teleporting
and done so the real the real question
there is what scale size we
last week and the real problem with all
all been
that for 75 years
the fish have not believed that
these Quantum process really applied
our scale size
that that was only a subatomic
phenomenon and the fact that
that applying this formulation
is mathematical
form to
acroscale objects
actually all object s and finding that
it still holds the information is
it emanated
all objects and
and what Shemp discovered is that the
emanations from any physical body
when considered as a group and let me
use a metaphor to
if you look at the little swirl on the
tip of your face
I didn't tell you much about you
if you look at this
identified
well the admissions from any physical
and analyzed and the way simple
done so
carries in vasion
medical object and you have you look at
it with regard to the berry phase
which is in the literature
um
physical
is
transferred
phase
as well
it really is weird
that desert the concept of an anti-wave
right
regular specific example here if
you and you hear the smell
the snapcation of the finger the snappy
is not in the brain so how does the
brain
that the snap is in some distance
from the brain itself was exactly the
same way back
radar
crate the
location of an image
or phase information it's phase
information just behind you get
information
virtual wave that is the equivalent of a
standing wave between itself and the
object now that's a modeling technique
of course but that is the way
the way the distance is
the facility can locate the target well
that is exactly
exact a Quantum holographic information
is
of the
wave
emitting object or if you're to perceive
it be a certain way that you must
resonate with
in order
so it's a well-establish
Ed and we have we have now attached
a test in a whole
uh circumstances
found in
as a matter of fact a colleague and
being written uh
and doing this sort of research has
recently written a book called called a
tangled
my discussing
and all of the experiment
experiment done
including that this type of phenomenon
virtually enters
all of the passive
of the so-called ESP phenomenon or all
of the circle I I just like this word
old paranormal phenomenon it's not para
at all normal yes it's exactly the way
the way things work at that level of
level I've always been a strong believer
in thought being a part of this process
as well it exactly is yes yeah now
it can be transferred transferred
transmitted and communicated and
verbally and in a
but nevertheless it is
a shame
the whole
oh let me let me say it in the following
way
we have traditional
tuition
are six cents that's the that's what's
in the lower that's a cultural lore we
call Intuition or sixth sense
but it's clearly a quantum
uh
information structure
it should be called our first sentence
was around long before our plan
our environment formed and our normal
are based upon
multiple environment so and
that the quantum information
so that's why
that's why I have to get the point
the point the intuition should really
become her first
we tied in and the heart of the process
upon which all the other century
informational Mega
Mega what about the fact of thought
being able to form and control the
reality that we live in that's that's
the
that's it
we've talked when talking about the
passive as
fast that is the active aspect yes of
course
and and that is the one that's a little
but all the principles that we're
talking we're talking here are important
and valid there
on their own now I have no
wall shorts
attentional
that's very clear
that intention
helps create reality I won't say it
totally creates reality but it certainly
can
the physical reality now I have studied
the healing mechanism which
would have been discussed for millennium
the healing mechanism
um
the processes
some
are gifted
that Pete really have this fine tune
like some of the healers I've worked
with and urine Yeller in particular I
have the Israeli psychic that I worked
with for years ago and it's still quite
and
type of
enough and all of us can do it to a
certain extent
stand it
but the more you're able to do
it if we break down our barriers
so there's a number of things that work
against us as well that not only
genetically but
self-esteem and
nature as well yeah of course we're
always trying to cut ourselves short
sometimes I think that our best
intentions go down the tubes it seems
that when we think we're going to have a
good day and we truly believe that we
have a good day I mean we think we're
not we don't
that's right and our mindset our belief
system our mindset is very fundamental
to all of this absolutely vitally
important
and uh expensive
cocaine change things
for a company
my bottom line as I look at this and try
to look at the
edge of the following is to say that we
live in
and create
create self-organizing
as a trial and error
participatory Interactive
not locally interconnected evolutionary
system
and that is our my description
live in and are part of because we're
intimately
with his
and that's primarily what
formalism shows you
is that everything in the universe
interconnected
level
what we're dealing with here is a
universe that shows its energy in two
forms
as structure we call it matter
and energy as information
of consciousness
with their inter
they remain
if we
call that and this is a proposition
if we call that
that Quantum correlation of particles
the most
awareness
then we're starting to build up this
whole concept we know is consciousness
and that's me project
now you have founded an organization The
Institute of
science
could you tell the listeners a little
bit about that organization because I
believe you have chapters
across the country and when I was
looking on their website I noticed that
there's one right here in Allentown
Pennsylvania well we certainly
addiction 30 years ago 30. almost 35
years ago now in
early 19th
Century in early 1970 73. in order to
to follow up on my inside
base
uh
uh from the point of view of science
because that was not a subject science
has
all horror will be one mechanics
the Cartesian notion that body mind
spirituality
belonged to two different Realms of
reality it was simply none of
null of mine and
do interact and the quantum formulation
but nobody has really pushed that
uh during the 20th century until
that's what I started to do in 1973
was to bring the
[Applause]
and use the tools of science to say
there is real science here and that's
what no other Institute scientists
his course
and over the last 35 years yes we've
been quite successful
and we're in about 30
30 uh
into our own investigation
and
study today one
women well that um
chapter studies what are some of the
tools that are utilized to measure some
of this phenomena well the basic
perceptual tools first of all Faraday
cages
the very first
in other words it is a Quantum not local
phenomena
the neurosciences have now gotten into
and there's a lot there's a lot of
Neuroscience
means to understand
black girl
earlier
say that the brain
which is true
but then going further ensuring see how
it is working is for neural
sync at this point
and uh
so what we have been doing for quite a
number of years is
replicating and validating
many of these interfaces
field
trying to pursue it
trying to
help people move toward
let's say a more
in their thought structure to move
toward a belief system
that is a result of this phenomenon
there is a connection
is that the world and the universe is
totally interconnected in some Mysteries
and
approaching that from the point of view
it sounds very much like the new thought
movement which was at the turn of the
surgery
yeah one of one of my most influential
books
been by William Walker Atkinson which is
a thought and the Law of Attraction
exactly yeah and there's a series of
books that were written you know back
then where part of the new thought
movement right yeah
doing is putting scientific meat on the
bones of those ideas
yeah which they didn't have available to
them back then they didn't have any of
this science
William James is very instrument
earlier
and helping us too and brother in
helping to get these ideas
to move and now purely
late in the
trillion down the 21st century
we have been able to
the mechanism that in the quantum
holographic mechanism
show that there is a physical phenomenon
involved here
they're very basic
basic fundamental level
of how we perceive
receiving yeah well I had read one time
that one of the reasons why we cannot
detect
from one individual to another with ESP
is the fact that it's not traveling from
one point in space to another to begin
with
yeah
it
and it also is a pair
in nature that Quantum correlation is
tied up very much with the spin
the spend uh
and
as far as we can tell at this
this better complete in and of
themselves
we have to have all of these Central
the information
coming in and give it meaning
we're giving meaning to information is
just more information
that you connect with your
with you the base of your
third worldview how does it fit in how
does this
and fit into your world view and you
give it meaning
based upon that
of course into all of that
have different paths
like neutral particle can precisely
about exactly the same path
to individuals living
way we all have a slightly different
world of you
and we give me to all the events in our
dependent upon that
and that's one of the reasons why we
come out with so many opinions on the
same
including who's got
ta finder yes for years yeah you have a
DVD out precisely on this topic which is
called
hologram if you tell the listeners a
little bit about that I notice you have
a whole series of DVDs and Publications
as well and we'll have a link going over
to your web page and listen
over there I actually have a copy copy a
Quantum hologram coming in myself it
should arrive either today or tomorrow
you're talking I don't know
but the paper called Nature's mind
and then the DVD that
is called the view from space and that
which described experiences but
that led me to exactly
exactly what we're talking
and both of those are available at your
website to order from you that's right
available on the on the website okay
is there anything else that you'd like
to add to all this and uh well maybe for
some of the listeners now we have a lot
of school kids that are listening too
and I imagine this may be a little bit
of a rough show for them to uh to get
through but perhaps if yeah
it is very sophisticated but it's so
it's so basic as well once you have an
understanding it's something I've been
following all my life and actually lived
my life and I believe that this is
actually the basis of holography
a visual holography one of the things
that we can say right here is that
nature has been using holography in this
sense a long long time before we ever
discuss
ion that's very it's a very good way of
putting it yeah yeah is there anything
else you'd like to add to the
conversation I would say also to the
young people the young the students that
might tune in and listen to this
work as important as going that's going
to Moon and
the impetuation
uh
start working this year
this year but it's all a part of the
evolution of our society and our
evolution of our
and hopefully it will help us find ways
to
the very beginning of the
Space Age
you think your book man Fuller pointed
out where the crew of spaceshipers and
we're mutinous crew and how
to move this group and that's exactly
where we still are these
yeah that must have been some ride on
that Saturn V well it was it was a great
adventure and what more can an Explorer
want
these days it's
the place that no humans have ever been
like
like another planet
and then to bring story back
that's a question
is to be part
of our crew of people
that experiment that you conduct
with folks back here on Earth that was
to prove that their the disc
right that that well that was their
intent and we did conduct the that the
ESP experiment uh
exactly in the fashion that
in the
in the world particularly
and we
around that and we got exactly the same
result but he
could he do
that's wonderful
well I want to thank you for being on
the
on this what's nice about having
internet radio is the fact that we can
include links and since we've just
even if we could say we even scratched
the surface
folks can have the links to
sources that are available for them to
get more information
yes Dr Mitchell thank you so much it's
been an honor you've been thank you
thank you
[Music]